<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>[emacs lisp] on Iskander (Alex) Sharipov technical blog</title>
    <link>https://quasilyte.dev/blog/tags/emacs-lisp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in [emacs lisp] on Iskander (Alex) Sharipov technical blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://quasilyte.dev/blog/tags/emacs-lisp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Goism objects layout model</title>
      <link>https://quasilyte.dev/blog/post/goism-objects-layout-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quasilyte.dev/blog/post/goism-objects-layout-mode/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Goism project requires Go pointers emulation inside Emacs Lisp code.
This document describes how to achive (almost) full functionality with potential to have optimizations that eliminate some of the emulation-related overhead.
The actual implementation can diverge. Only initial design is outlined.
Struct representation Go structures represented by lists.
Empty struct run-time value is unspecified, but it satisfies Go spec requirements.
type a1 struct { f1 int } // a1{1} // (list 1) type a2 struct { f1, f2, f3, f4 int } // a2{1, 2, 3, 4} // (list 1 2 3 4)  For the very small (1-3 fields) objects lists are a better choice than vectors, but generally, vectors are more memory-efficient and provide faster random access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Emacs Lisp compiler intrinsics</title>
      <link>https://quasilyte.dev/blog/post/writing-emacs-lisp-compiler-intrinsics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quasilyte.dev/blog/post/writing-emacs-lisp-compiler-intrinsics/</guid>
      <description>The problem Given a particular programming task in Emacs Lisp, you almost always should implement it with function. Sometimes, macro is a proper tool.
Even more rarely, cl-define-compiler-macro may be your choice.
All these methods are safe to use. They almost certanly will not break with newer Emacs versions.
One interesting task that can not be implemented efficiently with approaches that are outlined above is imperative return statement.
Emacs Lisp lacks this kind of flow control and this is a problem we are goind to attack today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Lisp multi return values</title>
      <link>https://quasilyte.dev/blog/post/elisp-multi-return-values/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quasilyte.dev/blog/post/elisp-multi-return-values/</guid>
      <description>The missing feature Did you ever wrote a function in Emacs Lisp which should return more than one result?
Emacs Lisp has no native support for multiple return values, but provides cl-lib that emulates it in a Common Lisp style.
In this article I will show that cl-values is suboptimal and can be replaced without any sacrifices to the convenience.
Naive solution cl-lib implements cl-values in terms of list. This approach is naive because each time you return with that, an allocation is involved.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>