<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Iskander Sharipov technical blog</title>
    <link>https://quasilyte.github.io/blog/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Iskander Sharipov technical blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 01:39:59 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://quasilyte.github.io/blog/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dispatch tables in Go asm</title>
      <link>https://quasilyte.github.io/blog/post/go-asm-dispatch-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 01:39:59 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quasilyte.github.io/blog/post/go-asm-dispatch-tables/</guid>
      <description>Dispatch tables When you want to execute particular code path depending on some kind of tag/opcode or other integer value that can be easily mapped into index, dispatch tables can speed things up compared to the sequence of comparisons and conditional jumps.
In interpreters, this technique is often used as an alternative to switch-based dispatch.
It&amp;rsquo;s called direct threading in that domain. Each opcode corresponds to table index that contains machine code address that can execute operation specified by the opcode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goism objects layout model</title>
      <link>https://quasilyte.github.io/blog/post/goism-objects-layout-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quasilyte.github.io/blog/post/goism-objects-layout-mode/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Goism project requires Go pointers emulation inside Emacs Lisp code.
This document describes how to achive (almost) full functionality with potential to have optimizations that eliminate some of the emulation-related overhead.
The actual implementation can diverge. Only initial design is outlined.
Struct representation Go structures represented by lists.
Empty struct run-time value is unspecified, but it satisfies Go spec requirements.
type a1 struct { f1 int } // a1{1} // (list 1) type a2 struct { f1, f2, f3, f4 int } // a2{1, 2, 3, 4} // (list 1 2 3 4)  For the very small (1-3 fields) objects lists are a better choice than vectors, but generally, vectors are more memory-efficient and provide faster random access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Emacs Lisp compiler intrinsics</title>
      <link>https://quasilyte.github.io/blog/post/writing-emacs-lisp-compiler-intrinsics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quasilyte.github.io/blog/post/writing-emacs-lisp-compiler-intrinsics/</guid>
      <description>The problem Given a particular programming task in Emacs Lisp, you almost always should implement it with function. Sometimes, macro is a proper tool.
Even more rarely, cl-define-compiler-macro may be your choice.
All these methods are safe to use. They almost certanly will not break with newer Emacs versions.
One interesting task that can not be implemented efficiently with approaches that are outlined above is imperative return statement.
Emacs Lisp lacks this kind of flow control and this is a problem we are goind to attack today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go assembly language complementary reference</title>
      <link>https://quasilyte.github.io/blog/post/go-asm-complementary-reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quasilyte.github.io/blog/post/go-asm-complementary-reference/</guid>
      <description>Third flavour of x86 assembly language This article is heavily inspired by AT&amp;amp;T VS Intel/Microsoft assembly syntax comparison page. It helped me very much in the past.
Many tools understand both AT&amp;amp;T and Intel style assembly. Go derived Plan9 toolchain, so you should learn third kind of assembly language. It will not accept anything else.
In this document:
 Comparison of Plan9/Go and AT&amp;amp;T/GNU assembly; Some non-obvious details that are not described anywhere else; Links to useful resources;  Check external resources for information that is missing here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go nested functions and static locals</title>
      <link>https://quasilyte.github.io/blog/post/go-nested-functions-and-static-locals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quasilyte.github.io/blog/post/go-nested-functions-and-static-locals/</guid>
      <description>Symbol visibility Default symbol visibility should be as narrow as possible. This means that you use globals with internal linkage instead of external, local variables rather than globals, hide class-related constants inside it&amp;rsquo;s scope, and so on.
If function is only called inside particular function, it should become a nested function.
Most of these rely on the language support.
Go has quite simple model of scopes and symbol visibility. User-defined identifier can be local or package-local (global).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Path to convenient C FFI in Go</title>
      <link>https://quasilyte.github.io/blog/post/cgo-funcall/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quasilyte.github.io/blog/post/cgo-funcall/</guid>
      <description>DWIM-style FFI CGo is a widely adopted way of calling C functions from Go: low level C FFI which does many things behind the scene, but exposes only minimal functionality that is required to interact with C.
CGo does no implicit conversions or data copying during C functions call, even int and C.int are not compatible. Code that uses this mechanism without wrappers (bindings) will be polluted with explicit slice/array copies and type conversions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RISC-V: custom instruction and its simulation</title>
      <link>https://quasilyte.github.io/blog/post/riscv32-custom-instruction-and-its-simulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quasilyte.github.io/blog/post/riscv32-custom-instruction-and-its-simulation/</guid>
      <description>Agenda This article shows how to add a new instruction to RISC-V and simulate it.
These topics are covered along the way:
 Whole GNU riscv toolchain installation; Implementation of a new instruction for spike RISC-V ISA simulator; Manual instruction encoding in C/C++; Custom instruction simulation (with visible output); [riscv32-]GCC plugin development;  You may find associated repository useful.
Many things can go wrong. Be prepared to fix upcoming issues by yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Lisp multi return values</title>
      <link>https://quasilyte.github.io/blog/post/elisp-multi-return-values/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quasilyte.github.io/blog/post/elisp-multi-return-values/</guid>
      <description>The missing feature Did you ever wrote a function in Emacs Lisp which should return more than one result?
Emacs Lisp has no native support for multiple return values, but provides cl-lib that emulates it in a Common Lisp style.
In this article I will show that cl-values is suboptimal and can be replaced without any sacrifices to the convenience.
Naive solution cl-lib implements cl-values in terms of list. This approach is naive because each time you return with that, an allocation is involved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C broken defaults</title>
      <link>https://quasilyte.github.io/blog/post/c-broken-defaults/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quasilyte.github.io/blog/post/c-broken-defaults/</guid>
      <description>State of the C C fits its niche quite well. If you want relatively simple, ubiquitous and efficient language there is no much room for selection.
It &amp;ldquo;evolves so slowly&amp;rdquo; because it is already quite complete. Most of the parts that can be improved without making C yet another bloated language require breaking changes.
 C could be designed better if we accept older code invalidation.
 &amp;hellip;but in reallity it is impossible to achieve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQ</title>
      <link>https://quasilyte.github.io/blog/post/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quasilyte.github.io/blog/post/faq/</guid>
      <description>Report an issue If you:
 Found a typo; Think some material is inappropriate or incorrect; Want to propose a new article;  &amp;hellip; or you looking for a way to contact author,
just open new Github issue.
Try to be polite and precise in your words, please.
Subscribe Currently, the only way to &amp;ldquo;subscribe&amp;rdquo; for blog updates is to watch blog-src repository.
Go to the linked repository and locate displayed button in the top-right part of the window.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>